<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communities on Pony</title>
    <link>http://www.ponylang.org/community/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communities on Pony</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Pony Developers</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ponylang.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>http://www.ponylang.org/community/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ponylang.org/community/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, gender identity and expression, level of experience, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to having a code of conduct as an anti-harassment policy, we have a small set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recurse.com/manual#sub-sec-social-rules&#34;&gt;social rules&lt;/a&gt; we follow. We (the project maintainers) lifted these rules from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recurse.com&#34;&gt;Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen these rules in effect in other environments. We&amp;rsquo;d like Pony community to share a similar positive environment. These rules are intended to be lightweight, and to make more explicit certain social norms that  are normally implicit. Most of our social rules really boil down to “don&amp;rsquo;t be a  jerk“ or “don&amp;rsquo;t be annoying.” Of course, almost nobody sets out to be a jerk or annoying, so telling people not to be jerks isn&amp;rsquo;t a very productive strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the anti-harassment policy, violation of the social rules will not result in expulsion from the Pony community or a strong warning from project maintainers. Rather, they are designed to provide some lightweight social structure for community members to use when interacting with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-standards&#34;&gt;Our Standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using welcoming and inclusive language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracefully accepting constructive criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on what is best for the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing empathy towards other community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of sexualized language or imagery and unwelcome sexual attention or
advances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trolling, insulting/derogatory comments, and personal or political attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public or private harassment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing others&amp;rsquo; private information, such as a physical or electronic
address, without explicit permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other conduct which could reasonably be considered inappropriate in a
professional setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Our Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers are responsible for clarifying the standards of acceptable behavior and are expected to take appropriate and fair corrective action in response to any instances of unacceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or reject comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions that are not aligned to this Code of Conduct, or to ban temporarily or permanently any contributor for other behaviors that they deem inappropriate, threatening, offensive, or harmful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct applies both within project spaces and in public spaces when an individual is representing the project or its community. Examples of representing a project or community include using an official project e-mail address, posting via an official social media account, or acting as an appointed representative at an online or offline event. Representation of a project may be further defined and clarified by project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enforcement&#34;&gt;Enforcement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be reported by contacting the project team at coc@ponylang.org. All complaints will be reviewed and investigated and will result in a response that is deemed necessary and appropriate to the circumstances. The project team is obligated to maintain confidentiality with regard to the reporter of an incident. Further details of specific enforcement policies may be posted separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers who do not follow or enforce the Code of Conduct in good faith may face temporary or permanent repercussions as determined by other members of the project&amp;rsquo;s leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;Attribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct is adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, version 1.4, available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/&#34;&gt;http://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-rules&#34;&gt;Social Rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-feigning-surprise&#34;&gt;No feigning surprise.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule means you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t act surprised when people say they don&amp;rsquo;t know something. This applies to both technical things (&amp;ldquo;What?! I can&amp;rsquo;t believe you don&amp;rsquo;t know what the stack is!&amp;rdquo;) and non-technical things (&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t know who RMS is?!&amp;rdquo;). Feigning surprise has absolutely no social or educational benefit: When people feign surprise, it&amp;rsquo;s usually to make them feel better about themselves and others feel worse. And even when that&amp;rsquo;s not the intention, it&amp;rsquo;s almost always the effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-well-actually-s&#34;&gt;No well-actually&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A well-actually happens when someone says something that&amp;rsquo;s almost - but not entirely - correct, and you say, &amp;ldquo;well, actually…&amp;rdquo; and then give a minor correction. This is especially annoying when the correction has no bearing on the actual conversation. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we aren&amp;rsquo;t about truth-seeking or that we don&amp;rsquo;t care about being precise. Almost all well-actually&amp;rsquo;s in our experience are about grandstanding, not truth-seeking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-subtle-isms&#34;&gt;No subtle -isms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last social rule bans subtle racism, sexism, homophobia, transphobia, and other kinds of bias. This one is different from the rest, because it covers a class of behaviors instead of one very specific pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subtle -isms are small things that make others feel uncomfortable, things that we all sometimes do by mistake. For example, saying &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s so easy my grandmother could do it&amp;rdquo; is a subtle -ism. Like the other three social rules, this one is often accidentally broken. Like the other three, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal to mess up – you just apologize and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a subtle -ism in the Pony community , you can point it out to the relevant person, either publicly or privately, or you can ask one of the project maintainers to say something. After this, we ask that all further discussion move off of public channels. If you are a third party, and you don&amp;rsquo;t see what could be biased about the comment that was made, feel free to talk to the project maintainers. Please don&amp;rsquo;t say, &amp;ldquo;Comment X wasn&amp;rsquo;t homophobic!&amp;rdquo; Similarly, please don&amp;rsquo;t pile on to someone who made a mistake. The &amp;ldquo;subtle&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;subtle -isms&amp;rdquo; means that it&amp;rsquo;s probably not obvious to everyone right away what was wrong with the comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any part of the code of conduct or social rules, please feel free to reach out to any of the project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>http://www.ponylang.org/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ponylang.org/community/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are committed to providing a friendly, safe and welcoming environment for all, regardless of gender, sexual orientation, disability, ethnicity, religion, or similar personal characteristic. Our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ponylang.org/community/code-of-conduct/&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; sets the standards for behavior in all official Pony forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important community resources for those who are new to Pony are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#ponylang, our IRC channel on &lt;a href=&#34;https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23ponylang&#34;&gt;freenode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/user&#34;&gt;Users Mailing List&lt;/a&gt; for discussion of all things Pony that don&amp;rsquo;t involve the development of Pony itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for help with Pony and can&amp;rsquo;t get a response in #ponylang, we advise that you send an email to the Users Mailing List.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ponylang.org/blog&#34;&gt;News, blog, whatever you want to call it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talks-articles-and-more&#34;&gt;Talks, Articles and more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be more than just a list link here. Intro text etc,
but, that can come later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ponylang.org/community/planet-pony/&#34;&gt;Planet Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chat&#34;&gt;Chat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in having a real time conversation about Pony, your best bet is the #ponylang IRC channel on &lt;a href=&#34;https://freenode.net&#34;&gt;freenode&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://irclog.whitequark.org/ponylang/&#34;&gt;Public logs for #ponylang&lt;/a&gt; are available if you need to catch up on conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mailing-lists&#34;&gt;Mailing Lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We host all our mailing lists with &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.io&#34;&gt;groups.io&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll need a &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.io/register&#34;&gt;groups.io account&lt;/a&gt; to sign up for any of our mailing lists. By joining any of the Pony mailing lists, you will also be automatically added to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/pony&#34;&gt;an announce only broadcast list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Pony user looking for assistance or to  discuss writing Pony code, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/user&#34;&gt;Users&amp;rsquo; mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to contribute to Pony, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/dev&#34;&gt;Developers&amp;rsquo; mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in finding out when our Virtual Users&amp;rsquo; Group is meeting or when new videos are posted, you should join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/vug&#34;&gt;Virtual Users&amp;rsquo; Group mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;users-groups&#34;&gt;Users&amp;rsquo; Groups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currenly have 3 users&amp;rsquo; groups; one virtual and two in-person. At this time, the New York City and London users&amp;rsquo; groups rarely meet. Your best bet for a users&amp;rsquo; group at this time is the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/vug&#34;&gt;Virtual Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt;. In general, it meets about once a month via &lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/search/sort:latest?q=pony-vug&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt; of past presentations are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to attend an in-person meetup, sign up for the mailing list to be informed the next time a meeting is occuring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/london&#34;&gt;London Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pony.groups.io/g/nyc&#34;&gt;New York City Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in setting up a users&amp;rsquo; group in your area and would like to host the mailing list on groups.io, drop us a line and we&amp;rsquo;ll get you set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-survey&#34;&gt;Community Survey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We run a yearly community survey to find out what the Pony community currently looks like. So far, &amp;ldquo;yearly&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;once&amp;rdquo;. If you are interested in learning a bit more about the community you&amp;rsquo;ll be joining, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ponylang.org/blog/2016/03/state-of-the-stable-2016/&#34;&gt;2016 State of the Stable&lt;/a&gt; community survey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pony-development&#34;&gt;Pony Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in helping to develop Pony, we have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ponylang.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;variety of resources&lt;/a&gt; to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Pony</title>
      <link>http://www.ponylang.org/community/planet-pony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ponylang.org/community/planet-pony/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t have a Pony blog aggregator at the moment, so in the meantime, we have this manually edited stand in. It&amp;rsquo;s like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TRAl48Ucgmw&#34;&gt;early curated days of Yahoo!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/202387915&#34;&gt;Pony Vug #8: Andrew Turley: Prime Cuts: The Best Pieces Of Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zestedesavoir.com/articles/1329/decouverte-du-langage-pony/&#34;&gt;Découverte du langage Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soyyomakesgames.wordpress.com/2016/10/10/ponys-capabilities-made-simple/&#34;&gt;Pony Capabilities made simple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/187451870&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #7: Nick Pruhs: Designing an Actor Model Game Architecture with Pony &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/2016/sessions/pony-language-provably-safe-lockless-concurrency&#34;&gt;Pony - A Language for Provably Safe Lockless Concurrency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R6T8ytKV6dc&#34;&gt;Pony: Co-Designing a Type System and a Runtime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/181099993&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #6: Andrew Turley: The Art of Forgetting - Garbage Collection in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zartstrom.github.io/pony/2016/08/28/reference-capabilities-in-pony.html&#34;&gt;Reference Capabilites in Pony for everybody&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/178522513&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #5: George Steed: A Principled Design of Capabilities in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/175746403&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #4: Simple Value-Dependent Types in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2016/07/18/borrowing-in-pony.html&#34;&gt;Borrowing in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://maniagnosis.crsr.net/2016/07/push-parsing.html&#34;&gt;Push-parsing and Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/172129187&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #3: The Actor Model and Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/168247590&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #2: Using the Pony FFI in Anger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/pony&#34;&gt;Using Pony for Fintech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/news/2016/03/pony-fintech&#34;&gt;Using the Actor-model Language Pony for FinTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2016/05/11/exploring-actors-in-pony.html&#34;&gt;Exploring actors in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2016/05/04/bang-hat-and-arrow-in-pony.html&#34;&gt;Bang, Hat and Arrow in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/163871856&#34;&gt;Pony VUG #1: Writing Generic Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2016/03/15/closures-in-pony.html&#34;&gt;Closures in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jtfmumm.com/blog/2016/03/06/safely-sharing-data-pony-reference-capabilities/&#34;&gt;Safely Sharing Data: Reference Capabilities in Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monkeysnatchbanana.com/2016/01/18/pony-patterns-waiting/&#34;&gt;Pony Patterns: Waiting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.acolyer.org/2016/02/18/ownership-and-reference-counting-based-garbage-collection-in-the-actor-world/&#34;&gt;the morning paper: Ownership and Reference Counting Based Garbage Collection in the Actor World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.acolyer.org/2016/02/17/deny-capabilities/&#34;&gt;the morning paper: Deny Capabilities for Safe, Fast Actors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/interviews/clebsch-pony&#34;&gt;Pony designer Sylvan Clebsch on the Actor-Model Language Pony, Garbage Collection, Capabilities, Concurrency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monkeysnatchbanana.com/2015/12/19/inside-the-pony-tcp-stack/&#34;&gt;Inside the Pony TCP Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2015/12/17/cross-compile-pony-programs-for-android.html&#34;&gt;Cross compile Pony programs for Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2015/12/16/c-linkable-libraries-with-pony.html&#34;&gt;C linkable libraries with Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.monkeysnatchbanana.com/2015/12/13/deconstructing-a-pony-echo-server/&#34;&gt;Deconstructing a Pony echo server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/darach/my_little_pony/master/my-little-pony.html&#34;&gt;Presentation slides for &amp;ldquo;My Little Pony&amp;rdquo; talk at CodeMesh 2015 in London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2015/11/04/a-quick-look-at-pony.html&#34;&gt;A quick look at the Pony Programming Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cdn.rawgit.com/sylvanc/pony-lecture/master/agere2015.html&#34;&gt;Presentation slides for &amp;ldquo;Deny Capabilities for Safe, Fast Actors&amp;rdquo; paper on Pony type system at Agere 2015 in Pittsburgh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://panopto.imperial.ac.uk/Panopto/Pages/Viewer.aspx?id=2e47f3d3-95e1-45c9-97fd-a9e4f35c66b3&#34;&gt;Part two of &amp;ldquo;Actor-based programming in Pony&amp;rdquo; at Imperial Programming Lectures in London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://panopto.imperial.ac.uk/Panopto/Pages/Viewer.aspx?id=aba3f8f7-f050-447c-91c9-61e092d61e85&#34;&gt;Part one of &amp;ldquo;Actor-based programming in Pony&amp;rdquo; at Imperial Programming Lectures in London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.piotrbuda.me/2015/05/implementing-chat-application-with-pony-lang.html&#34;&gt;Implementing chat application with Pony lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KvLjy8w1G_U&#34;&gt;Video of CurryOn presentation on Pony at ECOOP 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techcast.com/events/bigtechday8/pranner-1450/?q=pranner-1450&#34;&gt;Video of Pony talk at TNG Big Tech Day 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doc.ic.ac.uk/~scd/Pony-WG2.16.pdf&#34;&gt;Pony presentation by Prof. Sophia Drossopoulou at the IFIP WG 2.16 (Programming Language Design)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://www.ponylang.org/community/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ponylang.org/community/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>